Guide to the Stanford University, Libraries, HighWire Press, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Libraries, HighWire Press, records
1993-2000
SC1012
HighWire Press.
3.25 Linear feet and 7.62 megabytes
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Materials were transferred from HighWire Press, 2010.
Information about Access
Access: Materials are open to research use.
Biographical/Historical note
HighWire Press is a division of the Stanford University Libraries producing online versions of peer-reviewed journals and scholarly content.
Scope and Contents note
The records primarily contain overhead slides for presentations on HighWire Press by Vicky Reich, 2000 and undated; titles include Electronic Publishing between Two Poles, The HighWire Perspective Electronic Journal License Agreements, What *Do* Librarians Want? and E-Materials: Barriers to Revolutionizing Scientific Information. Other materials include webpage printouts, 1999-2000, and conference materials from Preservation 2000.
Access Terms
Reich, Vicky.; Libraries and electronic publishing.
Collection Contents
- Records, 1999-2000; Accession 2010-139; 1 Linear feet
  - Expanding the Print Journal to Fit the Online World. Vicky Reich [overhead slides] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - HighWire Press webpage printouts in overhead slides (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Electronic Publishing between Two Poles. Vicky Reich [overhead slides] (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - The HighWire Perspective Electronic Journal License Agreements. Vicky Reich [overhead slides] (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - HighWire Press webpages, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Overhead slides (current) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Preservation 2000, conference materials (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - STKE Virtual Journal, webpages, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Two presentations by Vicky Reich: “What *Do* Librarians Want?” and “E-Materials: Barriers to Revolutionizing Scientific Information” [photocopies of slides] (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Records, 1993-1998; Accession 2011-053; 2.25 Linear feet
  - AAAS Annual Meeting, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Access control, outlines, email, forms, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - ACM [Association for Computing Machinery] proposal/project, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Advisory Council, HighWire Press presentation, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - AJR, New Orleans, presentation materials, 1998 Feb (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Allerton Institute, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - ALPSP [Association of Learned and Professional Society Publishers] seminar materials, Parallel Publishing, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Annual Reviews, online project proposal, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Business Models for E-Publishing, presentation materials, notes, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Conway, Morna, "Publishing on the Web Ahead of Print," text and notes, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Cooper, Noreen, "Public Interest Intrapreneurship," text and letter, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - CSTR emails, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - CSTR meeting, email, drafts, notes, etc., 1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Demo at Moscone Center, email, notes, and other materials, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Demoing HighWire, outlines, memos, email, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Dolphin, Kimberley A. "Hip or Hype? Electronic Journals: A Descriptive Study in Three Parts", 1994 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - E-Journal Task Group, emails, memoranda, etc., 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Economic Problems of Copyright, presentation by Mike Lesk, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Gorden & Breach, transparencies (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The High Wire Partnership, Vicky Reich, transparencies, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - HighWire talk, Vicky Reich, transparencies, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - IuK Workshop, paper abstracts, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry (Electronic publication of the), proposal, notes, memos, etc., 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - JBC, emails about website/data issues, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - JBC materials, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry project, notes (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - NASIG, HighWire Workshop, "Technology and the Effects of Electronic Journals on Libraries," by Vicky Reich, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - NDLF/Digital Library project meeting, notes, 1996 Dec. 15 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - NSF-2: “The Computer Science Technical Report (CS-TR) Project: Considerations from the Library Perspective,” Greg Anderson, Rebecca Lasher, and Vicky ReichNSF-2: “The Computer Science Technical Report (CS-TR) Project: Considerations from the Library Perspective,” Greg Anderson, Rebecca Lasher, and Vicky Reich, circa 1995 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Reich, Vicky, transparencies, correspondence and other materials, 1995-1998 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Science [Magazine] notes, proposal, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Science On-Line Feedback, email responses, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Scientific publishing, assorted presentations and other materials, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Scientific publishing, marketing, assorted materials, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Social Impacts of Digital Libraries, workshop materials, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Stanford Digital Library Project, Andreas Paepcke - original transparencies (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Stanford Digital Library Project, Andreas Paepcke and Vicky Reich - copies of online slides (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Stanford Digital Library Project, Shanghai conference, Vicky Reich's presentation, 1997 Nov (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Stanford Digital Library Project, Vicky Reich - copies of transparencies (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - SUL Electronic Media Copyright Policy, drafts, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Stanford University Digital Library Research Initiative, Vicky Reich, transparencies, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Taking a Journal On-Line: Practical Experiences by John Sack, photocopies of transparencies (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Terms and Conditions Workshop, Break-out Group Report, Vicky Reich, transparencies and notes, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Transparencies (general HighWire Press information) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Transparencies, HighWire Press web pages, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Unsorted memos, correspondence, copies of transparencies, etc., 1995-1996 and undated (Box 4, Folder 6-9)
  - Web Training for Faculty, email, outlines, etc., 1995 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Science Magazine Focus Group; recorded at Technology forecasters, Inc., 1996 Oct; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Science Magazine Focus Group; recorded at Technology forecasters, Inc., 1996 Oct; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Focus Group, Hyatt, Palo Alto., 1996 Oct; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Focus Group, Hyatt, Palo Alto., 1996 Oct; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)